[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trient tasa Advanced Training as you all
know I already published 71 YouTube
videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
Concepts from few videos onwards I've
started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacle and how can
you solve those obstacles while
automating the test cases by using
trient
tasa so this is our lesson 72 in terms
of overall tric TSA automation training
and this is our obstacle 30 in terms of
realtime scenarios please do subscribe
to the channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you in this lesson I'm
going to teach you how can we solve an
obstacle where you need to click an
object on the screen based on the screen
width by using an inbuilt module within
tricentis tasa so now let us go and see
in detail what is the obstacle that we
need to solve for so here is our
obstacle the name of obstacle is red
stripe which is categorized as easy let
us go for
it so you can see here click on button
label generate and then click on red
stripe that
appears the number below the button
informs you how far to the right from
the edge of screen stripe has appeared
so let us first click on generate button
so now you can see a red line is
appeared and this number represents how
far this red
line is to the right from the edge of
your screen so that means the width of
your screen until this red stripe is 62
let me generate again so now the width
is 25
and this is your remaining
75 again now it is
66% so basically the red stripe is at
the 66% of your width of your screen
okay so now we need to click on this red
color line so how can you click on this
red color line that is what we need to
automate so now to automate this
scenario let us go to prent
Tas so as usual we are going to capture
the test objects under obstacles folder
so right click on this obstacles folder
select scan
application so now select the
application that you would like to scan
and click on scan
so here I don't see the number property
here so now here I don't see the number
here for that let us go to filter and
expand the filter one click still I
don't see the number another click now
you can see here the number see this is
your number which is your div element
let us select this
number you can see here the property of
the number is ID number you should not
select your inner text because
this percentage keeps on changing
whenever you click on generate button so
this is not going to be constant so I'm
going to select ID number Tag div right
so these two are the elements that I
would like to select one and two both of
them are uniquely identified okay okay
so now let us name this
module as the name of your
obstacle copy and paste it
here and now save the
module and close your X scan so let us
go to
chasa here now this is our latest module
that
scan this one double click on this now I
should see two objects generate button
and your number so let me rename this as
number so now let us go to our left side
section which is test case section which
is in blue color so as usual I'm going
to create a new test case under
obstacles folder right click on this
folder
select create test case and name with
the same name of your obstacle double
click on this test case now to automate
the test case or to automate the
scenario drag this module and drop
here so here what I'm going to do I'm
going to name this as generate let's do
one
thing click
and generate so what I'm going to do
here I'm going to
Simply click on generate Button as soon
as I click on generate
button I have
to see what is the percentage of the
width where your red stripe will appear
so this is the percentage what I'm going
to do I'm going to buffer this value
into a variable here I'm going to say
inner
text equal to and store this into a
buffer called
num here your action mode should be
buffer right now I have stored the
buffer and then you need to click on
this red
button this red stripe you need to click
on this red stripe to click on
red to click on red stripe you have an
inbuilt function called let's go here
right
click search and ADD test
step and type click on screen so you
have a click on screen HTML right so
this is what you need to
select there is another click on screen
here which is mobile I don't want to
select that one I want to select click
on screen from HTML select this
one and here you need to provide caption
of
the browser or window what is the
caption you can see tricentis obstacle
what I'm going to do here I'm going to
enter
trient
UPS upster obstacle so I'm going to just
enter
partial information I'm going to enter
the partial title and then I'm going to
use the regular expression prent is
obst and anything it can have right so
the name is obstacle very big name
basically it has obstacle do test
automation obstacle right so I'm just
using the regular expression to
identify the caption and then what is
your
X coordinator and what is your y
coordinator X means what is your width
and what is
your height or what is your horizontal
component what is your
vertical
percentage R what is your horizontal
percentage and what is your vertical
percentage so here I'm going to call the
buffer that I have stored here so for
that Curly Braes open curly braces
capital B and now
your buffer name and close curly
bra so here I'm specifying that your
width is the 56 and what about this
vertical coordinator do you want me to
click on here here here here here where
so probably I can leave this as I can
provide any number I want because this
vertical
because this stripe is from bottom to
top right so better I provide the same
buffer name number here the same
percentage that I'm storing under buffer
I can keep the same or I can specify any
number I want but however to avoid
confusion I'm entering the
same the value that I'm storing under
buffer now let's save this let us mark
this as
completed so what we have done first by
using the module that we captured I'm
clicking on generate and then
immediately I'm storing the value that
is generated in the buffer and now by
using that buffer value I'm using an
inbuilt click on screen X
module where I'm specifying the
caption of your browser and then I'm
calling the buffer value here so that I
can exactly click on that red
stripe now let's save the test case now
let us regenerate
this and
then right click and run in scratchbook
see now it has regenerated the red
stripe and then he clicked on the red
stripe let me try again okay let me try
again so now there is no red stripe
right now let us run this now again
right click and running scratchbook
now it clicked on generate and then
which is 30 33% and then it clicked on
red stripe at 33% of the width of the
screen so if you go to your tricenter
tasa and you can see here the buffer has
been stored as 33 and then it is
clicking on screen with that
33% so hope you all understand the
concept if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos and don't
forget to like and share the video thank
you
[Music]